[Music]
Professor Dave and CH here we just learned
about enantiomers so we know that they are
pairs of molecules which are non-identical mirror
images of one another but what does this have to
do with how molecules behave do entiers have any
different properties let's investigate given that
enantiomers are precise I mirror images they
have nearly identical physical properties they
have exactly the same density polarity melting
point and boiling point one way of distinguishing
between a pair of an antier has to do with the
direction that they rotate plain polarized light
when a beam of ordinary light passes through
something called a polarizer only the light
oscillating in a particular plane will pass
through and this is said to be plain polarized
as light oscillating along any other plane is
blocked out any chyal compound will be optically
active meaning that it will rotate plain polarized
light by some angle depending on the structure of
the molecule as measured by and analyzed on
the other side of the molecule with respect
to the light source when looking at a pair of an
anti immerse they will rotate this light by the
same angle but in opposite directions one will be
dextrorotatory signified with a plus sign meaning
the rotation is clockwise and the other will be
Lev rotatory signified with a minus sign meaning
the rotation is counterclockwise we can measure
the optical activity of many different compounds
and tabulate them and testing the optical
activity of a sample is a way of determining
the enantiomeric purity of the sample if both
enantiomers are present in equal amounts the
dexr rotatory and Lev rotatory activity will
cancel out and the sample will not be optic
active overall if one enantiomer is pure
it will rotate the light according to the
tabulated value for that enantiomer and then if
the optical activity is some fraction of that
of the pure en antier we can do math to find
out the ratio of one enantiomer to the other
in the sample and so we now have a little more
context surrounding the concept of an antier
in the way of a specific application namely a
physical property that differs from one in antier
to the other we can think of optically
active as more or less a synonym for
Kyu but we also now know exactly what the term
means Professor Dave for che see you next time